<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.openstreetmap.josm</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-3.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <developer_name>JOSM developers</developer_name>
  <name>JOSM</name>
  <summary>Java OpenStreetMap Editor</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
    JOSM is an extensible off-line editor for ​OpenStreetMap (OSM) written in ​Java.
    </p>
    <p>
    It supports loading stand-alone GPX tracks and GPX track data from the OSM database as well as loading and 
    editing existing nodes, ways, metadata tags and relations from the OSM database.
    </p>
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
    <category>Geoscience</category>
    <category>Maps</category>
  </categories>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.openstreetmap.josm.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default" width="1024" height="576">https://josm.openstreetmap.de/svn/trunk/linux/josm-screenshot.png</screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://josm.openstreetmap.de</url>
  <updatecontact>josm-dev_at_openstreetmap.org</updatecontact>

<releases>
  <release version="14760" date="2018-02-01" >
    <description>
    major enhancements
        When unglueing a node from a way, retain the history on the node which gets assigned the tags. (r14653, r14662)
        Add tab with installation details in "About" popup (r14693, r14701, r14707)
    medium enhancements
        Improved "Zoom to selection" behavior (r14628, r14734)
        Allow to save active ValidatorLayer (r14667, r14668)
        Make auto-resizing Tags table to fit content optional and disabled by default (r14677)
        Display non default API URL in upload dialog (r14729)
    minor enhancements
        Imagery Preferences: harmonize cache size units (r14631)
        Imagery Preferences: collect all cache settings in the same tab (r14632)
        Detect preset wiki languages automatically (r14646, r14647, r14660, r14664)
        Status report: exclude file history, Overpass queries (r14671)
        Add Help buttons to several windows (r14655:14658, r14742:14745)
        Restore contextual menu of history dialog (r14676)
        GenericRelationEditor: bind Ctrl+Enter to okay action (r14679)
        Improve progressMonitor for internal osm (xml) importer (r14688)
        ChildRelationBrowser: add popup menu (r14713)
        Remove support for TagChecker configuration files i.e. tagchecker.cfg (r14727)
        Improve progress bar of history browser (14756)
        Add/improve/fix/change Internal Presets, Map Paint Style and Validation rules:
            Don't sort map_size values in information=map preset (r14621)
            Add 22000 as a valid voltage value (r14645)
            Add naming tags for relations: water/waterway/wetland (r14680)
            Fine tune unknown tags warning (r14696, r14739, r14750, r14751)
            Add Key:interval to presets (r14711, r14712)
            Add traffic_calming=dip, sort traffic calming presets more logical like in the wiki (r14714)
            Add type of zoo (r14715)
            Validate correct Key:interval syntax (r14728)
            Remove some false positve validator warnings of attraction=summer_toboggan (r14735) 
        More minor bug fixes, enhancements, stability improvements, translation updates, code improvements and code documentation, see SVN log messages of milestone 19.01 
    </description>
<release version="14620" date="2018-12-31" >
    <description>
    major enhancements
        Fixed many memory leaks (#17040)
        Fixed many outdated imagery entries (#16073)
        Animate the "Getting Started" page with shining stars 15 days around Christmas (r14578) 
    medium enhancements
        Auto-resize Tags table to fit content (r14476, r14613)
        Map paint: Improve performance of fill-image instruction (r14557)
        Map paint: Improve rendering time of partly visible complex shapes (r14582:14584)
        Validator: Improve performance of MapCSSTagChecker (r14469, r14474)
        Validator: Improve progress monitor (r14599)
        Validator: Warn about simple typos in tag values (#17055) 
    minor enhancements
        Support Internationalized domain names (IDN, r14496)
        Support user logins ending by " !" (r14404, r14406, r14480)
        Ignore MapCSS declarations starting with "-" to allow osmose extensions (r14481, r14489)
        Load Taiwan Government Root CA certificate (r14498)
        Update to latest ESRI projection definitions (r14568)
        Add/improve/fix/change Internal Presets, Map Paint Style and Validation rules:
            add 4wd_only, improve access preset layout (r14534)
            add shop=gas (r14575), building=carport (r14610)
            improve billboard and crane presets (r14560, r14574)
            improve sport=climbing presets (r14591, r14597)
            improve emergency=fire_hydrant preset (r14593:14595, r14608)
            warn about area:highway on unclosed ways and nodes (r14577) 
        More minor bug fixes, enhancements, stability improvements, translation updates, code improvements and code documentation, see SVN log messages of milestone 18.12     
    </description>
</release>
<release version="14460" date="2018-11-28" >
    <description>
    The height of each panel on the right side is saved when JOSM is closed.
    "Download as new layer" changed from a checkbox to an own button.
    </description>
</release>
<release version="14382" date="2018-10-28" >
    <description>
    Option to display object version in lists 
    </description>
</release>
<release version="14289" date="2018-10-02" >
    <description>
    Various enhancements for the correlation of images to gpx tracks 
    </description>
</release>

<release version="14178" date="2018-08-22" >
    <description>
    Display the language the abbreviation in name:xx keys stands for in the Tags/Membership dialog
    </description>
</release>
</releases>

</component>
